Edmon Garcia

Front-End Developer

09365458835 g.edmon25@gmail.com

DESCRIPTION

As a dedicated Front-End Developer with 2 years of experience, I am committed to crafting exceptional user experiences through clean and efficient code. My main tech stack includes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, along with other UI Frameworks such as MUI, React Bootstrap, and Bootstrap. I also have knowledge in integrating REST API and MySQL databases to create dynamic and responsive web applications. Pursuing my Bachelor's degree in Entrepreneurship, I am constantly seeking new ways to innovate and drive growth in the industry.

EXPERIENCE

Yakap Health, Inc. - Makati City - ReactJS Developer

September 2022 - April 2023

- Created reusable components to avoid DRY.
- -Actively participated in code reviews and troubleshooting to ensure efficient and high-quality code implementation.
- -Worked with the team to continually improve the product's functionality and user experience.
- Integrated RESTful APIs using Axios for seamless communication between the client-side and server-side.
- - Finish Track Page and Subpages.
- Continuously updated skills and knowledge of new technologies and frameworks to improve productivity and contribute to the success of Yakap Health. Inc.

Senti Al, Makati City - Cloud Engineer

February 2022 - July 2022

- Worked as a Front-end developer using Lit, JS and CSS.
- Implement UI Designs.
- Write clean and efficient code.

- Collaboration with other Senior Developers.
- Document the project.

Yakap Health, Inc. - Makati City - ReactJS Developer

July 2021 - January 2022

- Responsible for the creation of the Yakap Health alpha version of the web application
- Collaborate with CTO and Backend developer for success of the project.
- Responsible for integration of REST API.
- Design and created a mobile friendly web application using Bootstrap.
- Work closely with the Stakeholders for the verification of requirements as well as with UI Designer

SwQuity.io, Remote - Front-End Developer

May 2021 - July 2021

- During my stay at SwQuity I implemented UI. I was responsible for creating visually appealing and user-friendly web interfaces that meet the project's requirements and specifications.
- I used Sass as the main UI Framework for tweaking UI Designs.
- Integrated API using Axios and worked with both the Front-End and Back-end Team.
- I used Next JS, TypeScript and Sass.

Alaga Health, Quezon City - Mobile and Web Developer Intern

May 2021 - July 2021

- Trained in various Front-End and Back-end Technologies such as React, React Native, NodeJS, MERN Stack etc.
- Worked with other intern for our final project which is a Floating action chat that made of React JS and Firebase
- Built a wireframe from scratch with Figma for the Floating Action Chat Project
- I received an Exemplary Award for the CTO Department after the internship.

EDUCATION

Rizal Technological University, Mandaluyong - Bachelor of Science in Entrepreneurship

August 2019 - July 2023

- Trained and Equipped for Career and Entrepreneurship Venture.
- Created a Business Plan, Pitch Deck and competed with other school mates in Wadhwani Entrepreneurship Program.
- Registered a venture at DTI and created a Mobile Application Program for Agricultural Product which is part of our project in Business Plan Implementation
- Learned writing effective business plan, Feasibility Study, Market Analysis, Financial Analysis, Accounting, Export Marketing and Business Law

EDUCATION

Jose Rizal University, Mandaluyong - Accounting and Business Management(Senior High School) June 2017 - April 2019

- Learned fundamentals of Entrepreneurship, Accounting, Statistics, Economics, Research and Marketing.
- Participated in different seminars and Activities within our school.
- Joined *Dulaang Milenyal* as a Theatre Actor.

AWARDS

- Champion at 2021 FEU ACM Hackin Good Competition
- BEST CTO DEMO AWARDS Alaga Health
- TOP 30 SandBox PH